Contact

rshel64@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/randyshelafoe-msn-rn-cnl-949aba74 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

ICU

ACLS

BLS

Publications

Reducing Costs Secondary to Chemotherapy Induced or Exacerbated Heart Failure

Information Station-An Innovative Strategy to Engage Staff in Daily Unit Huddles

Randy Shelafoe, MSN, RN, CNI

Clinical Nurse Manager Portland, Oregon Area

Summary

A Critical Care RN working in acute care settings since 1998 with progressive leadership experience. I am interested in system and process development utilizing lean methodologies, transformational leadership skills, and evidence based patient centered care delivery models. I believe nursing is the backbone of the healthcare industry often looked upon as a cost rather than a budget saving opportunity. Nursing is key to an efficiently run, high quality, and safely run unit. As a transformational and servant leader, I strive to build upon the resources around me and develop committed teams to successfully and cost-efficiently meet our patient's quality healthcare needs.

Experience

Kaiser Permanente Nurse Manager CardioVascular Cath Lab July 2019 - Present (1 year 1 month) Clackamas, Oregon

Manage daily operations of a busy Cardiac Cath Lab. Responsible for budget, patient experience, 44 direct reports.

Kaiser Permanente contracted through The First String Healthcare Nurse Manager CardioVascular Cath Lab May 2018 - June 2019 (1 year 2 months)

Clackamas, Oregon

CV Nurse Manager. Filling CardioVascular/CCL management demands via transitional leadership assignments. Nurse Manager Cardiac Catheterization Lab 5/18-present.

5/18-10/18 PeaceHealth Hospital, Vancouver, WA 10/18-6/19 Kaiser Permanente, Clackamas, Oregon (signed on permanent)

Responsible for daily operations, expert in coaching, mentoring, productivity, staffing, evaluations, critical conversations, process improvement, staff development, education/competencies, team leadership. Interim management professional.

Houston Methodist CVICU RN March 2017 - March 2018 (1 year 1 month) Houston, Texas Area

Cardio-Vascular ICU RN.

CHI St. Luke's Health
Nurse Manager CardioVascular Cath Lab
May 2016 - January 2017 (9 months)
Houston, Texas Area

Patient Care Manager of an 11-suite cardiac catheterization lab & pre/post holding area at CHI Baylor St. Luke's Medical Center located in the Texas Medical Center. I oversee a team of 70 employees and the daily operations within BSLMC's Texas Heart Institute. Responsible for the day to day operations, budget, and implementing the department's strategic plan. Applying transformational and servant leadership skills utilizing a multi-interdisciplinary team approach as we provide the highest quality of safe, efficient, effective, timely, equitable, and ethical patient/family-centered care.

MD Anderson Cancer Center
Clinical Nurse Leader-Management
August 2014 - January 2016 (1 year 6 months)
University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center

Progressive Leadership Experience:

Lead & manage a nursing team.

Coordinate interdisciplinary teams insuring patient's needs are met.

Project management and implementation to continually update systems and processes using LEAN Methodologies.

Evaluate team's delivery of MD Anderson's caring factors and the language of caring.

Kaiser Permanente CVICU RN June 2011 - June 2014 (3 years 1 month)

Progressive Leadership Experience:

- Developed Evidence Based Policies and Procedures
- Developed and Conducted evidence based clinical study on reducing ICU delirium
- Earned an MSN as a Clinical Nurse Leader
- Developed and Implemented point of care clinical protocols to reduce ICU delirium
- Developed and Presented to administration family brochures for the reduction of ICU delirium
- Worked closely with the Medical Director to set delirium reduction strategy goals and objectives

O'Connor Hospital Charge Nurse, RN III October 2004 - June 2011 (6 years 9 months) San Jose, CA

Progressive Leadership Experience:

- · Promoted within clinical ladder to RN III, Charge Nurse
- Evaluated, developed and initiated cost efficient, lean, evidence based clinical protocols
- Developed and implemented Interventional Radiology (IR) department's orientation program
- Developed Evidence Based Policies and Procedures for the IR Department
- Created and implemented IR Pre and Post-Procedure Order Sets
- Clinical Nurse Educator and Speaker
- Hospital Committee Member; Stroke Team, Clinical Ladder, Policy and Procedure

HRN Services

Travel RN

October 2000 - October 2004 (4 years 1 month)

RN Travel Assignments in ICU, CVICU, Burn ICU, Step Down, PACU, IR

Virginia Mason Medical Center CVICU/ICU Staff RN October 1998 - October 2000 (2 years 1 month) Seattle, WA

Staff RN CVICU, ICU

Education

University of South Alabama

Doctor of Nursing Practice, Executive Nursing Administration · (2016 - 2020)

University of San Francisco

Master's of Science in Nursing, Clinical Nurse Leader · (2012 - 2014)

Minneapolis Community and Technical College

Associate's degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (1996 - 1998)

University of St. Thomas

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Business Administration/Management · (1982 - 1986)